Variability is crucially important for learning new skills.
可变性对学习新技能至关重要。
Consider learning how to serve in tennis.
不妨想一想学习网球发球的情形。
Should you always practise serving from exactly the same location on the court, aiming at the same spot?
你是否应该总是在球场上完全相同的位置练习发球，并且瞄准同一个点呢？
Although practising in more variable conditions will be slower at first, it will likely make you a better tennis player in the end.
在变化更多的条件下练习，虽然起初会慢一些，但最终很可能让你成为更出色的网球选手。
This is because variability leads to better generalisation of what is learned.
这是因为可变性会使所学内容泛化得更好。
This principle is found in many domains, including speech perception and learning categories.
这一原理见于许多领域，包括言语感知和类别学习。
For instance, infants will struggle to learn the category “dog” if they are only exposed to Chihuahuas, instead of many different kinds of dogs.
例如，如果婴儿只接触吉娃娃，而不是许多不同品种的狗，他们就很难学会“狗”这个类别。
“There are over ten different names for this basic principle,” says Limor Raviv, the senior investigator of a recent study.
“这一基本原理有十多个不同的名称。”最近一项研究的资深研究员利莫尔·拉维夫说。
“Learning from less variable input is often fast, but may fail to generalise to new stimuli.”
“从变化较少的输入中学习往往很快，但可能无法泛化到新的刺激上。”
To identify key patterns and understand the underlying principles of variability effects, Raviv and her colleagues reviewed over 150 studies on variability and generalisation across fields, including computer science, linguistics, categorisation, visual perception and formal education.
为了找出关键规律、理解可变性效应背后的原理，拉维夫和同事们梳理了150多项关于可变性与泛化的研究，这些研究来自多个领域，包括计算机科学、语言学、分类、视觉感知和正规教育。
The researchers discovered that, across studies, the term variability can refer to at least four different kinds of variability, such as set size and scheduling.
研究人员发现，在不同的研究中，“可变性”一词可以指至少四种不同的可变性，例如样本集的大小和编排方式。
“These four kinds of variability have never been directly compared—which means that we currently don’t know which is most effective for learning,” says Raviv.
“从来没有人直接比较过这四种可变性，这意味着我们目前还不知道哪一种对学习最有效。”拉维夫说。
The impact of variability depends on whether it is relevant to the task or not.
可变性的影响取决于它与任务是否相关。
But according to the “Mr. Miyagi principle”, practising seemingly unrelated skills may actually benefit learning of other skills.
但根据“宫城先生原理”，练习看似无关的技能，实际上可能有助于学习其他技能。
But why does variability impact learning and generalisation?
但可变性为什么会影响学习和泛化呢？
One theory is that more variable input can highlight which aspects of a task are relevant and which are not.
一种理论认为，变化更多的输入能够凸显任务的哪些方面是相关的、哪些不是。
Another theory is that greater variability leads to broader generalisations.
另一种理论认为，更大的可变性会带来更广泛的泛化。
This is because variability will represent the real world better, including atypical examples.
这是因为可变性会更好地反映现实世界，包括那些非典型的例子。
A third reason has to do with the way memory works: when training is variable, learners are forced to actively reconstruct their memories.
第三个原因与记忆的运作方式有关：训练富于变化时，学习者就不得不主动重构自己的记忆。
“Understanding the impact of variability is important for literally every aspect of our daily life.
“毫不夸张地说，理解可变性的影响对我们日常生活的方方面面都很重要。
Beyond affecting the way we learn language, motor skills, and categories, it even has an impact on our social lives,” explains Raviv.
除了影响我们学习语言、运动技能和类别的方式之外，可变性甚至还会对我们的社交生活产生影响。”拉维夫解释说。
“For example, face recognition is affected by whether people grew up in a small community or in a larger community.
“例如，人们是在小社区还是在较大的社区长大，会影响他们识别面孔的能力。
Exposure to fewer faces during childhood is associated with diminished face memory.”
童年时期接触的面孔较少，与面孔记忆力减弱有关。”
“We hope this work will spark people’s curiosity and generate more work on the topic,” concludes Raviv.
“我们希望这项研究能激发人们的好奇心，并催生更多关于这一课题的研究。”拉维夫总结道。
“Our paper raises a lot of open questions.
“我们的论文提出了许多悬而未决的问题。
Can we find similar effects of variability beyond the brain, for instance, in the immune system?”
我们能否在大脑之外，比如在免疫系统中，发现类似的可变性效应？”